Jane?
- Hi, Lisbon.
- What are you doing?
just working.
Okay, well, out here in the real world
we have a case. We have to go.
Yeah. Okay.
Let's go.
You think you're so mysterious.
I know what you're doing in there.
Oh, really? What?
You're making a list
trying to figure out who it is
- that you've met that's Red John.
- Not just met, shaken hands with.
How many people
are on that list, anyway?
A lot.
Got a male shooting victim.
Looks to be early 20s.
Happened about an hour ago.
No I.D.
- Who called it in?
- Bartender. We're getting a statement.
- What do the witnesses have to say?
- Not sure. Cho's talking to them.
- Has the coroner taken a look at him yet?
- Yeah, he's on his way.
What... what's that on his face?
- What?
- Oh, boy.
Happy anniversary!
- What's goin' on?
- Come in, everybody!
Ladies and gentlemen
ten years ago, Teresa Lisbon
left the San Francisco Police Department
to join the California Bureau
of Investigation.
Today she is without doubt
the rootinest, tootinest,
sharp-shootinest cop
in the whole state
of California.
- Happy anniversary, boss.
- Hear, hear.
So if we could start the music, please?
- I had no idea.
- Let's party!
- Congratulations, Lisbon.
- Thank you, Ron.
- Why did you do this?
- It was Rigsby's idea.
Yeah?
- Is he taking his clothes off?
- He is.
Oh, my God.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you, Ray.
Haffner. Good to see you.
You know, I really enjoyed
when we worked together.
- We should do it again sometime.
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
You mean when you
almost got me fired?
Yeah, that was a lot of fun.
Hey, can we grab lunch?
There's just something
I wanna discuss with you.
Yeah, sure.
All right. I'll call you.
Jane.
How come he doesn't like me?
You got lunch here, you got...
- Oh, look out.
- What?
Okay, that's enough.
Shoo. Okay?
It was fun.
But not my butt.
That was the office.
Homicide out in Placer County.
The team that was supposed
to cover for us today
can't make it out there.
Well, I don't think we can drag Lisbon
away from this.
- Can't we cover it, Cho?
- Yeah. Yeah, we can.
Okay. Where did you
find that guy?
That was fun.
But we're done, okay?
Oh, yeah.
Those are nice moves.
CBI. I'm Agent Cho,
this is Patrick Jane.
Rick Anaya. Chief here in Elliston.
Good to meet you. This way.
The bodies were found
in a secret basement
under the barn floor.
And what's with
the secret basement?
Yeah, probably built in the '20s
to hide booze during prohibition.
My dad, who was chief before me
said there used to be stills
all through these parts.
Kids were playing
in the barn
found a trap door,
went in, found some bones.
If you boys are still in town for dinner
Ella's Diner on Allen street...
best damn chili in town.
What's the coroner say?
Well, right now he's guessing
they died 20, 25 years ago.
He confirms three bodies in all.
What is it?
looks like
a shotgun pellet.
Yeah, we found some of those
under the bones.
Figured they fell out the body
as they decomposed.
No shell casings in here, though.
Must have shot them somewhere else
brought the bodies here.
- Anything else?
- Yeah, a couple of things.
High school class ring.
Guess it fell off one of them.
- We'll check that out. Is that it?
- No, this .38.
And one round's been fired.
Not in here, as far as we can tell.
You see that wire?
On the wrist?
See, I'm guessing at least two of the victims
were tied up with it.
This is very depressing.
I'm gonna wait outside.
The Red John symbol
was on the side of the barn?
- That's weird.
- Yeah.
Must have been there
15, 20 years.
Wonder what it means.
What did Jane say?
Nothing.
Wouldn't talk about it.
Okay.
Everybody feel as bad as I do?
Not if you feel
like you look.
I feel fine.
What time did you get back
to the party last night?
A little past 10:00.
Not that you noticed.
Yeah. That, Tequila
was a killer.
Did I,... Do anything embarrassing?
- Yes.
- Really? What?
Good morning.
Thank you for the party.
- It was very thoughtful.
- You're welcome.
But I am never gonna forgive you
for that stripper.
Where are we
with the three victims?
Coroner says they probably died
25 years ago, so 1988.
Talked to the ring manufacturer.
They traced it back
to a Lester Bradovich
who went to a high school in Dixon.
Checking him out now.
The gun that was found near
the bodies isn't registered.
No sign of the bullet
that was fired, either.
But I've got techs sweeping the area
around the barn.
Nice work. Let me know what you find.
She was kidding, right?
- About never forgiving?
- Nope.
How was the rest of the party?
Torture. That can never,
ever happen again.
- Ten years, huh?
- More, actually.
Every year with you
counts as two.
- Are those from the crime scene?
- Yes.
- This can't be a coincidence, can it?
- There's no such thing.
These murders happened ten years
before Red John was even active.
A shotgun was never
his weapon of choice.
True.
Well, what happened?
How'd it get there?
They're excellent questions.
You know where to find me.
Got a hit on Lester Bradovich.
He had a couple of arrests
in the mid-'80s.
Small stuff. Possession,
drunk and disorderly.
No record of him
after 1987.
- Family?
- A brother in town
but here's the weird thing...
nobody ever filed a missing
persons report on him.
That's odd. You and Rigsby go
and see what the brother has to say.
All right.
So what did I do last night?
Come on. I'm dying here.
You got up on the table and sang
"Bohemian Rhapsody."
I do a pretty good
Freddie Mercury.
That's not so embarrassing.
Maybe not for you.
- Gordon Bradovich?
- Yeah?
We need to talk to you
about your brother Lester.
Lester? Are you serious?
You're...you're positive
it's Lester?
We're waiting for final confirmation
from the coroner
but we're pretty sure, yeah.
This is just unreal.
When was your last contact
with your brother?
Oh, God, sometime
in the late '80s.
So you haven't seen him
in almost 25 years
but you never reported him missing.
Why is that?
- We didn't think he was missing.
- I don't understand.
Lester had been
in a lot of trouble.
Drugs and scrapes
with the law, and...
then, when he was about 24
he...he joined with this,
this group.
A little weird, but very strict,
very disciplined.
Seemed to straighten him out.
He, he got calmer,
stopped getting into trouble.
And what does that have to do
with his disappearance?
Well, after about a year with them
he, he came to my dad and me
and he said that he had
to break off all contact
with his biological family.
Yeah. His group said
that this was the only way
his true identity could emerge.
We were pretty hurt.
But Lester...he was totally
matter-of-fact about it had to be done.
That was...
the last time I talked to him.
Now you're telling me
he's been dead all this time?
I just...I-I don't even know
what to think.
- What's the name of the group?
- Vision.
No. Visualize.
You've heard of it?
- Hello?
- "Teresa."
- Ray Haffner. I've been looking for you.
- Hey, Ray. What's up?
I was wondering if we could
snag that lunch today
at 1:00 at the State House Cafe.
Sure. You wanna tell me
what this is about? I'm intrigued.
Then my plan is working.
I'll see you then.
- What does he want?
- Lunch.
Mr. Jane. Agent Lisbon.
Good to see you again.
Jason Cooper.
Brother Cooper.
Last time, I saw you was, when Bret Stiles
had just uncovered your plan
to take over this place.
I thought he would have
gutted you like a trout
but here you are.
Bret's generosity is only exceeded
by his capacity for forgiveness.
Is Mr. stiles here?
We need to speak with him.
Unfortunately, Bret was called out
of the country this morning.
Convenient.
But he asked me to answer
any question you have.
Won't you come this way?
There's tea.
Lester Bradovich
belonged to our church.
I believe there's a good chance
that all three of the bodies you found
were church members.
- Well, what makes you say that, Mr. Cooper?
- These murders occurred in 1988.
At that time, Visualize
owned the Elliston farm.
Everyone who worked there
was a member of the church.
Why did Bret Stiles
own a farm?
He had a dream.
He saw Visualize controlling an agricultural
empire based on wheat
but he wanted each of the farms
to be a self-sustaining bio-community.
So they had to raise their own
vegetables and livestock.
It was a grand vision.
The church bought
a half-dozen farms.
Half a dozen? All run by people
that knew nothing about farming?
Let's just say that enthusiasm
was a poor substitute for expertise.
They all failed in a year or two.
Lester Bradovich ran the Elliston farm
with two others...
Martin Talbot
and Allan Charney.
That's what we have on them.
In July of 1988, when we hadn't
had any word for some weeks
we sent people down
to investigate.
They found it empty.
We assumed that Bradovich
and the others had abandoned it.
Why didn't you file a missing
persons report?
They were adults.
We weren't their parents.
We assumed they'd run off.
Besides, we have found,
then and now
that the police rarely take
church complaints seriously
when we do file them.
But we are all horrified
by what happened.
We'll do anything at all
to assist in your investigation.
You have my word.
Martin Talbot was older.
No family.
That explains why nobody
was looking for him.
Allan Charney
had family in Idaho.
They did file a missing person's report
but nothing ever came of it.
There's no other information
on either one of them.
All right, call Charney's family
and let them know what happened.
Visualize is sending down their files
on Elliston farm.
Go through 'em.
There might be something useful.
All right. Will do.
I hate cold cases. No evidence, no witnesses
and where do you start?
Oh, it's not so bad.
You know what you need?
- A viable suspect?
- Big bowl of chili verde.
Come on. Let's go.
Ella's Diner?
Best damn chili in town,
I'm told.
Please tell me
we're not here for chili.
Of course not.
We're here to find a killer.
- What are we doing here, Jane?
- Look around.
The collective memory of this entire town
is in this room.
Anything that happened in the last 50 years
you'll find out about it here.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Lemon for your tea?
- No, thanks.
Ma'am, we're with the CBI.
We're investigating some murders
that took place in town
20 years back.
You mean the three bodies
in the barn?
Yeah, I heard.
The victims were from
a group called Visualize
that owned the farm.
Do you know anything about that?
All I know is that
they found three dead guys.
- Can I get you anything else?
- No, thanks.
- Collective memory?
- If I may...
who told you about
the three dead guys?
- Everybody knows.
- Yes, but who told you?
Look, I don't wanna
get anybody in trouble.
Oh, of course. Thank you.
Patrick Jane. I'm with the CBI.
What's your name?
Miles MacCambridge. Why?
- This is my colleague, Teresa Lisbon.
- Hi.
- You're the town gossip, I take it?
- I am?
Retired schoolteacher,
by the looks.
Who's your source
on the murders?
Former student,
I'm guessing?
Am I in some kind of trouble?
- Possibly.
- No, you're not.
Jury's still out.
We're investigating
the murders
and we'd really appreciate it
if you could tell us
anything about that farm
that we found the bodies at.
Oh, yeah. Well, it's...it's been
through a lot of hands.
It's not very good land.
No one's worked it
for at least a decade.
What about the group, Visualize?
They owned the farm
back in the mid-'80s?
Sure, I remember them.
They stuck out.
Pretty useless as farm folk.
How did they get along
with the other people in town?
Were there any conflicts
that you remember?
They mostly kept to themselves.
I remember one person
bitching about 'em...
a farmer named Tom Crayhew.
Couldn't tell you what he was upset about
too long ago.
we really appreciate it.
Thank you.
- So I'm not in any trouble?
- Jury's still out.
- You're fine, sir.
- Looky here.
Took me up on
my recommendation, I see?
- Tell Elena to put your check on my tab.
- Aw, that's okay.
Please. It's a long tab.
Enjoy.
You don't like him.
- Former student?
- Yes.
Mean kid? Pulled on the girls' pigtails?
He's chief of police
which is a pretty powerful position
around here.
If you'll excuse me.
Is this the stuff
from Visualize?
Yeah, it's mostly letters
from the farm to Visualize
asking for more help
and more money.
And Bradovich, Charney, and Talbot
were the only full-time workers.
But Visualize was sending
temporary people all the time...
some members,
some potential recruits.
Their names weren't even
recorded most of the time.
Most of the time?
Yeah, there's one lead...
a guy named Peter Dibuono
is listed as working at the farm
in '86 and '87.
He might be able to tell us something.
I reached him on e-mail.
- He's coming in to talk.
- Good.
You and Rigsby go to Elliston.
Talk to a farmer named Tom Crayhew.
Apparently he had some sort of
beef with the Visualize farm.
I'll be back in an hour.
- Where you going?
- Lunch.
No, no. My hat's off.
I only lasted two days as Jane's boss.
He nearly killed me.
So you...you ...clearly
know things that I don't.
- He is not that hard to handle.
- Really? Seriously?
'Cause I know a couple...
thousand people
who would disagree with that.
So... ten years?
People keep on saying that.
I don't know why.
I don't feel any different.
I'm hoping it means
you're ready for a change.
Oh, what is that
supposed to mean?
I'm leaving CBI.
I've lined up some capital.
I'm starting my own firm.
Security and investigations
for high-end clients.
I was wondering if you'd consider
coming with me.
Right.
You're one of the top agents in the division.
Everyone knows it.
You... you deserve a position
commensurate with your gifts.
- I am flattered, Ray, but I like my job.
- Yeah, I like my job, too.
I'd like it better if I'd had a raise
in the past three years.
California's broke,
if you didn't notice.
It's not about the money.
That's the starting salary.
That'll keep you in
leather jackets, I think.
It's not about the money.
I like what I do.
It's a good job. It's good work.
- Is it the work, or is it Jane?
- He's part of the work.
Sure. And you guys...you guys
have a track record
I-I understand why
you wanna stick with that.
But if there's one thing
that I've learned about Jane
it's that catching bad guys
is a game to him
and...and he's gonna
quit someday.
Maybe because he gets
Red John
maybe because...what...
he just gets bored.
When that happens,
you're gonna be on your own.
Driving out to some crime scene
in the middle of nowhere at 5:00 a.m.
asking Rigsby what sort of sad story
you gotta unravel this time.
Is that what you really want?
Because I think
you deserve better.
Think about it.
Mr. Crayhew?
Mr. Crayhew, we're with CBI.
Open up, please!
- I will not be bullied!
- Put the gun down.
You cannot make a man
render unto Caesar
that which he does not
choose to render.
- What?
- Sir, whatever the problem is
we can work it out.
Just put the gun away.
Federal income tax is an illegal taking
under the Fifth Amendment
of the United States Constitution
and I will not pay it!
- Sir, we're not with the I.R.S.
- Says you.
We have nothing to do
with your taxes.
We wanna talk about some killings
at a nearby farm.
You're not federal agents?
You're not here to collect?
No, sir. California Bureau
of Investigation.
Now put the gun down.
Do it now.
Yeah, I remember
those clowns from Visualize.
That land's right next to mine.
Killed everything they... they touched.
- Plus they were thieves.
- Why thieves?
Well, they stole my damn water.
I got a stream up that way.
They diverted it into their fields
like I wouldn't notice.
So me and my 12-gauge went
to talk it over with them.
I told those wackadoodles
to stop stealing my water
and one of 'em
pulled a revolver.
I thought we were gonna
have a shooting right there.
Do you recall
what kind of revolver it was?
Nope.
Was one of these...
the man that threatened you?
It was that one.
He was wound up.
Had that look, you know?
Just ready to go.
I truly thought I was gonna have
to shoot him right there.
But I didn't.
I didn't.
I swear to God.
But I don't condemn
whoever did shoot him, though.
You've heard how
they treated their animals?
No. How?
They... tortured 'em, basically.
Unnatural stuff.
- Satanic ritual stuff.
- Really? You know that for a fact?
If you don't believe me, talk to the Vet.
She was on 'em all the time about
how they were treating their stock.
She was ready to call
the county on 'em.
- And what's this vet's name?
- I think she retired now.
Preston. That's it.
"Hello, Lisbon."
Are you ever gonna
let me in there again?
- "How was lunch?"
- Lovely. Haffner offered me a job.
Really?
- You gonna take it?
- Right now I'm considering it.
Come on. We have to go talk to the Vet.
Oh, my God.
This one's for Doug.
- Dr. Ellen Preston?
- Oh, no, I'm...
Dr. Preston's my mom.
I'm Holly Preston.
Holly. Pretty good
with those dogs.
Oh, well, thanks.
I should be.
I'm with them all day.
I run a doggy day care.
- Is there something I can do for you?
- We're with the CBI.
We need to ask your mother
some questions.
Is that a problem?
She was diagnosed with Alzheimer's
about eight years ago.
She still responds
but she's not very good at talking
to people anymore.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, don't be.
She looks peaceful.
She is... mostly.
You've probably heard
we found three bodies
on a nearby farm.
25 years ago, the farm was owned
by a church called Visualize.
Does that ring a bell?
I've heard about them.
They made kind of a splash.
Hi, little boy.
Who's a good boy?
Yeah. Oh, he likes that.
You like that?
Is... that what you wanted to
talk to my mom about?
We heard that she was concerned
about the way some of the animals
were being treat.
We just wanted to know
what that was about.
Rumor has it they were
performing satanic rituals.
What?
We'd heard there may have been
some unnatural acts going on.
Have you been talking
to Tom Crayhew?
- Why? Does it sound like him?
- Oh, exactly like him.
I would remember if my mom
thought something was happening.
There were no rituals.
I think my mom was just concerned
that the farm was failing.
People take it out on the animals
once a place goes south.
- Did you ever go up there?
- No.
I was 16, and I was
all about boys then.
I wouldn't go to the farm with my mom
if I could avoid it.
Well, all the academic achievements
suggest you were focused
on a little more than just boys.
Well, maybe now and then
but that was a long time ago.
Is that all you wanted to ask about?
- Yes.
- Yeah. Thank you for your time.
- Jane. Jane.
- Yes. Who's that, huh?
Is that good?
That's really good.
- Jane?
- That's really good.
- Agent Van Pelt?
- Yes?
Father Peter Dibuono.
You asked to see me?
Obviously, I haven't been a member
of Visualize for some time.
If I were to be kind to my younger self
I would say that my time with them
was an early stage
in a long spiritual journey.
What if you
weren't being kind?
I was a stupid punk
who didn't know any better.
Bret Stiles says a lot
of things that sound good
if you don't think
about 'em too hard.
Some of what he says
makes sense, though.
Yes. And there's a core of truth
in every good lie.
All that talk about self-actualization
can be very, very seductive.
Oh, it's not just seduction.
What's wrong with wanting to be the most
powerful version of you you can be?
If you were a good person
it would just make you
an even better one.
Well, it depends on how
you look at it, I guess.
You wanted to ask me
about the Elliston farm?
- You worked there, right?
- No, I ran it.
From mid-'86 to late '87.
That was a crazy time.
There was a lot of pressure from Visualize
to make that place work.
We just didn't have the people
or the expertise.
And that's why they brought
Bradovich into take over.
Lester Bradovich?
And Lester... he was a true believer.
He worked people insanely hard...
18, 20 hours a day.
No one lasted long except for him,
Talbot and Charney.
After I left, um, I heard...
this is just a rumor...
that...that Lester had been
giving people drugs
to keep them working
when they were tired.
- What kind of drugs?
- I don't know. I don't know.
Speed, I would guess.
But he must have been desperate
because there were so many ex-addicts
in the church at that time
that Visualize
was very strict about drugs.
If he couldn't get the drugs from the church
where would he get 'em?
I have no idea.
Father Dibuono.
Patrick Jane.
Agent Van Pelt told me you used to work
on the Elliston farm.
- That's right.
- May I show you something?
Do you know what that is?
Sure.
Yeah, I saw that.
When?
A few months after I left the farm
I, I went back for a visit
and that's when I saw it.
Talbot said that some kid who
worked on the farm... he did it.
"Some kid," that's all
he said about it?
Yeah, yeah. Some kid.
How old was Talbot?
50-something?
So anyone under the age
of 30 could be "some kid".
You know, I asked Talbot what it meant
the smiley face.
He said, "what does anything mean?"
But he said it with this really deranged
expression on his face.
There was a bad vibe
about that place.
Evil.
I didn't spend more
than half an hour there
and I never went back.
And you've never seen that image
anywhere else ever since?
No. No. But I've been out
of the country a lot.
Missionary work.
Central America.
Is something the matter,
Mr. Jane?
No. No, not at all.
Appreciate your time.
When the murders occurred
Bradovich was pushing the farm workers
as hard as possible.
They were stealing water
from neighboring farms
and still failing
to make the farm produce.
How does any of that
get the three of them killed?
Well, I checked on Crayhew.
He spent some time with a right-wing
militia in the mid-'80s.
The county sheriff still thinks
he's got a lot more guns on that farm.
It wouldn't surprise me.
What about the forensics team
that was searching the farm?
Did they come up with anything?
- Nothing yet. They're still looking.
- Stay on 'em.
I'm interested in the drugs
the good father mentioned.
He said it was just a rumor.
Well, if Bradovich is working
them around the clock
I'm betting they had
a little chemical help.
And if they didn't get it from Visualize
then where did they get it from?
Who knows?
Everyone who could tell us is dead.
Not everyone.
Nope.
Don't remember any of 'em.
Of course, I was just...
17 at the time.
Not likely to run
into boys like these.
And, as far as drug deals in 1988
I couldn't tell you anything about that.
Wasn't bustin' drug dealers quite yet.
Would your office have any record
of drug arrests back then?
A lot of the old files
have been archived.
They're in some warehouse in Fresno.
I can send somebody to go look
but it's gonna... it's gonna take a while.
Could do that.
Or you could just tell us
what drugs you sold 'em.
Excuse me?
You were dealing drugs
back then, weren't you?
And they were clients.
Whatever gives you the idea
that I dealt drugs?
You're self-indulgent.
You're corrupt.
You pretended
not to know Bradovich
when clearly,
you recognize him.
You knew we were gonna
talk about drugs.
So why lie about not selling 'em?
Look, I'm...I'm not
sitting still for this, okay?
You withhold information from us
during this investigation
it's considered obstruction of justice.
They'll take your badge for that.
You might have to start paying
for that chili verde.
I might have dealt
a little in high school.
Lot of people did, okay?
It wasn't no big deal.
And by the way, I'm pretty sure the statute
of limitations has expired on that.
Did you sell drugs to Bradovich?
This is between us, right?
Law officer to law officer?
Chief...
He was looking for Speed
to keep his people working.
I sold him some.
But right away,
he came back for more.
A lot more.
I didn't have the kind
of quantity he wanted
so I put him in touch with some
serious guys I knew in Stockton.
Scary dudes.
Hell, maybe they killed 'em.
I'm gonna need those names.
Two of the drug dealers
Anaya gave us are dead.
The other one's
on death row in Texas.
I've got a call in to the Department
of Corrections
to see if I can interview him.
Oh, remember the missing bullet
from the gun we found near the bodies?
Techs finally found it.
It was buried in the dirt
in front of the barn.
Like somebody
had shot into the ground.
Where outside the barn?
Right in front
of the big painted face.
So what do you think?
Should I go to Texas
and talk to this guy?
By all means, take a trek
to the Lone Star state.
But I think I can solve
this case quicker.
How?
Get everyone we've interviewed
to Ella's Diner
first thing tomorrow morning.
- Well, why the diner?
- For the coffee, of course.
Hey, Ray.
Hey. I was, just checking in.
Seeing if you had a chance
to think about the offer.
I think you already know my answer.
- You're missing out on something big.
- I'm sure I am.
How's the case?
You getting anywhere?
We're making progress.
Did you get anything from
the stuff Cooper sent down?
No, not much.
Ray, Jason Cooper's name
isn't on that board.
So?
How did you know
that he sent us material?
Someone on your team
must have told me.
No one else knew
except myself and Jane.
Did somebody from
the church tell you?
Ray?
Are you a member of Visualize?
As a matter of fact, I am.
I don't talk about it much.
People tend to take it the wrong way...
the way that you're taking it
right now, I think.
- Oh, that's not true.
- Really?
No.
Look, I was a screwed-up kid.
I was headed down a bad path
and some people from Visualize
took an interest
and helped straighten me out.
I don't think that Bret Stiles is God.
You know, he just happens to say
some things that I believe.
The money to fund your agency...
is that coming from Visualize?
Some, not all.
Teresa, stop looking at me
like I just turned into a robot.
It's just me.
- Just in time, Lisbon.
- Morning, Jane. Nice party.
- Can I get some of that coffee?
- Nope.
This is only for the suspects.
- What?
- For who?
- What did you say?
- That's right.
You're all here because one of you
killed Lester Bradovich
Martin Talbot, and Allen Charney.
Why would I kill three members
of my own church?
Well, because the farm was failing
and Bret Stiles didn't want that to happen.
But maybe it wasn't you.
Mr. Bradovich here was angry with his brother
for abandoning his family.
Even if I was, why would I kill
the other two guys?
Who knows how a homicidal maniac thinks?
- Homicidal maniac?
- I was 16, Mr. Jane.
Yes, but your mother was an adult
and she was angry with the farmers
over how they were
treating the animals.
Are you seriously saying
my mother killed these people?
You're right.
Maybe it was the priest.
He was angry because he was displaced
as the farm's leader.
No, I wasn't.
Then there's the angry farmer
and the police chief.
Whoever did this,
it was definitely one of you
and in a moment,
we're gonna find out which one.
But first...
more coffee, anyone?
- No. No. No. No. No.
- Mom. Mom.
- No, no, no.
- Mom...
Mom, take it easy.
What's her problem?
Why's she so upset?
She recognizes the symbol.
There was one at the farm.
- You mean the face on the barn?
- Right.
And she knows
what happened underneath it.
Are you saying she's the killer?
We're gonna have to ask your mother
some questions.
- No. You can't.
- Ms. Preston, you got no choice.
She won't understand.
Well, we're gonna have to try.
- Come on. We'll treat her right.
- No. It's not her.
It's me.
You thought it was me
when we met, didn't you?
I thought that was a possibility.
Young woman, high-achieving
ends up running a doggy day care.
Suggested something went wrong
along the way.
Yeah.
That sounds about right.
My mother was concerned
about the Visualize farm.
I was riding along when she made
a visit in the area.
"And she said
she wanted to check on them"
"to see what was going on."
"It had rained that day..."
"So the ground was wet."
You stay here.
I'll be just a minute.
Next thing I knew,
I heard someone shouting.
- Don't tell me what to do!
- There are laws.
- I don't care about any of your laws!
- Laws that say this animal
has to be fed and taken care of!
And if you won't take care of it,
I will report you!
I... I should...
You want me to take care of it? Fine!
I'll take care of it!
He looked so crazy.
Just out of his mind.
Well, he was amped up on Speed.
He'd been sleep-deprived for weeks.
He was out of his mind.
What happened next?
Oh, you son of a bitch!
Mom!
I thought he was gonna
kill my mother.
I had to do something.
Hey!
Get off her!
I-I don't understand...
Where were Charney and Talbot?
How did they get shot?
I don't know.
What?
I-I don't know anything
about them, I swear. I...
It wasn't me.
What wasn't you?
Holly?
What happened
when you hid the body?
My mother was sure I could go to jail.
And she couldn't let that happen.
She wouldn't let that happen.
"She knew there was a basement
in the barn."
"So we went down there"
"and that's when we found
the other two."
Talbot and Charney's bodies
were already there?
I-I guess it was them.
Did you see anything else?
Anything at all?
No.
After we dumped the body
we got out of there
as fast as we could.
"I had a feeling..."
"Someone was there with us."
Someone was watching us.
- Hey. You got a second?
- Sure.
Word is Holly Preston's only gonna face
manslaughter charges for the homicides.
That true?
We suggested it to the D.D.A.,
and he agreed.
Really?
She claims she did it in self-defense
and we believed her.
- She'll serve time.
- Three guys got killed.
She only killed one of them,
and it was in self-defense.
That's what she says.
Are you in the business
of taking killers at their word?
I believe her.
Did someone from Visualize
ask you to talk to me?
Because you've never come to my office
and questioned my arrests before.
Yeah, I might have gotten some calls.
Might've heard some concern
that you pushed for lighter sentences
because the victims were church
and maybe you don't like the church.
Absolutely not.
Would you be willing to push for
a murder charge
have another talk with the D.D.A.?
Absolutely not.
Okay. Had to try.
Thank you for hearing me out.
Hey, I-I heard about Jane's trick.
How did he make that symbol
appear on the table?
Lemon juice.
Kid's invisible ink.
The heat from the coffee pot
made it appear.
Lemon juice. Of course.
Hey, Ray...
You said that you joined Visualize
as a teenager.
- So 1988, you would have been 21?
- Yeah, about that.
Did they ever send you to work
at the Elliston farm?
Were you there?
Lisbon, we're still friends, right?
Why would you ask me that?
- Lisbon.
- Hi, Jane.
What's up?
I had something I wanted to tell you
but I've had enough of this.
- Let me in, or else.
- Or else what?
I don't know, but you're not
gonna like it.
Are we partners or what?
Come in, partner.
Wow.
What did you want
to tell me?
Visualize absolutely refuses
to let us look at a membership
list from 1988
or any other year before or after.
And since they're a recognized
religious organization
no judge will give us a warrant.
If Red John was a member
of Visualize in 1988
- we'll never know.
- Figures.
Never mind.
We know that Red John
was at Elliston farm in 1988.
That is a huge leap forward,
Lisbon. Huge.
How so?
I recalled all the names
of the 2,164 people
that I met and shook hands with
since Red John murdered my family.
I might have missed
one or two, but not many.
807 of those names
were women.
And Red John's
probably not a woman.
Another 949 were men
that I had brief encounters with
that I never saw
or heard from again.
That leaves 408 names.
And Elliston farm will exclude
a whole bunch more.
I'm getting close, Lisbon.
I'm getting very close.
Tell me some of the names.
There's gotta be some
that are at the top of the list.
Sure.
There's some
interesting names.
Well, tell me.